But they woke at dawn, as usual, and suddenly remembering the glorious thing
that had happened, they all raced out into the pasture together.
A little way down the pasture, there was a knoll that commanded a view of most of
the farm.
The animals rushed to the top of it and gazed round them in the clear morning light.
Yes, it was theirs.
Everything that they could see was theirs.
In the ecstasy of that thought, they gamboled round and round. They hurled
themselves into the air in great leaps of excitement. They rolled in the dew.
They cropped mouthfuls of the sweet summer grass. They kicked up clods of
the black earth and snuffed its rich scent.
Then they made a tour of inspection of the whole farm and surveyed, with
speechless admiration, the plowland, the hayfield, the orchard, the pool, the spinney.
It was as though they had never seen these things before, and even now they
could hardly believe that it was all their own.
Then they filed back to the farm buildings and halted in silence outside
the door of the farmhouse.
That was theirs, too, but they were frightened to go inside.
After a moment, however, Snowball and Napoleon butted the door open with their
shoulders, and the animals entered in single file, walking with the utmost
care for fear of disturbing anything.
They tiptoed from room to room, afraid to speak above a whisper,
and gazing with a kind of awe at the unbelievable luxury, at the beds with their feather
mattresses, the looking glasses, the horsehair sofa, the Brussels carpet, the
lithograph of Queen Victoria over the drawing-room mantelpiece.
They were just coming down the stairs when Molly was discovered to be missing.
Going back, the others found that she had remained behind in the best bedroom.
She had taken a piece of blue ribbon from Mrs. Jones's dressing table and was
holding it against her shoulder and admiring herself in the glass in a very foolish manner.
The others reproached her sharply, and they went outside.
Some hams hanging in the kitchen were taken out for burial, and the barrel of
beer in the scullery was stove in with a kick from Boxer's hoof.
Otherwise, nothing in the house was touched.
A unanimous resolution was passed on the spot that the farmhouse should be
preserved as a museum.
All were agreed that no animal must ever live there.